(Episode 89)
(Episode 89)
By any chance, is this person's name Catherine?
By any chance, is this person's name Catherine?
Tae Ho?
Tae Ho?
No.
No.
This woman is not my sister.
This woman is not my sister.
I don't know what's going on,
I don't know what's going on,
but why are you asking about my sister?
but why are you asking about my sister?
Please don't get the wrong idea. It's not your sister,
Please don't get the wrong idea. It's not your sister,
it's this woman we want to know about.
it's this woman we want to know about.
This woman is posing as your sister, Catherine.
This woman is posing as your sister, Catherine.
It's a case of identity theft. We must find her link to Catherine.
It's a case of identity theft. We must find her link to Catherine.
That's what we want to find out.
That's what we want to find out.
I wonder.
I wonder.
Do you think she was close to Catherine?
Do you think she was close to Catherine?
No.
No.
Kang Se Ri.
Kang Se Ri.
That woman...
That woman...
We dated briefly.
We dated briefly.
Is Lee Tae Ho in the office building?
Is Lee Tae Ho in the office building?
Yes.
Sí.
But I haven't even sent him the catalogue or the contract.
But I haven't even sent him the catalogue or the contract.
He must be on his way up, then.
He must be on his way up, then.
Actually, I don't think he's here to see you, sir.
Actually, I don't think he's here to see you, sir.
He went to DH Holdings' Investment and Development Team a while ago.
He went to DH Holdings' Investment and Development Team a while ago.
We'd like to know more about Kang Se Ri.
We'd like to know more about Kang Se Ri.
Could you tell us about her?
Could you tell us about her?
I'm sorry, but that's a private matter.
I'm sorry, but that's a private matter.
I'm not even sure what's going on myself.
I'm not even sure what's going on myself.
It looks like I need to do my own digging.
It looks like I need to do my own digging.
We can talk again after that.
We can talk again after that.
All right. I'm sorry if we were too personal.
All right. I'm sorry if we were too personal.
Not at all.
Not at all.
Anyway, our purpose was to meet with Designer L, wasn't it?
Anyway, our purpose was to meet with Designer L, wasn't it?
I'll email you the proposal we discussed on the way over.
I'll email you the proposal we discussed on the way over.
Okay.
Bueno.
I need you to review it favourably.
I need you to review it favourably.
If we showcase an exhibition hall revamped with Designer L's style,
If we showcase an exhibition hall revamped with Designer L's style,
I think it will be a meaningful gift for the visitors.
I think it will be a meaningful gift for the visitors.
My whole team is really excited about it.
My whole team is really excited about it.
I'll think it over.
I'll think it over.
Well, I should get going.
Well, I should get going.
Should we meet separately tomorrow?
Should we meet separately tomorrow?
No, we got the answer we needed.
No, we got the answer we needed.
We'll see you around.
We'll see you around.
Take care.
Take care.
Hello.
Hola.
I heard you were in the building and came to say hello.
I heard you were in the building and came to say hello.
- I hope I'm not interrupting. - Not at all.
- I hope I'm not interrupting. - Not at all.
We had just finished up and were about to see him out.
We had just finished up and were about to see him out.
Goodbye, then.
Goodbye, then.
Please let me know about the proposal.
Please let me know about the proposal.
Yes, I'll be in touch.
Yes, I'll be in touch.
Please come to my office.
Please come to my office.
Thank you, but I'm only here to meet Designer L,
Thank you, but I'm only here to meet Designer L,
which is why I didn't contact you beforehand.
which is why I didn't contact you beforehand.
It's about the project I mentioned, the one I want to work with L on.
It's about the project I mentioned, the one I want to work with L on.
I came to propose it to her in person.
I came to propose it to her in person.
Of course, this is scheduled for after my YL Group contract ends,
Of course, this is scheduled for after my YL Group contract ends,
so you don't need to concern yourself.
so you don't need to concern yourself.
May I ask...
May I ask...
what your meeting with DH Holdings was about?
what your meeting with DH Holdings was about?
It turns out Patrick is good friends with a long-time U.S. client.
It turns out Patrick is good friends with a long-time U.S. client.
I guess he heard I was coming here and reached out to Patrick himself.
I guess he heard I was coming here and reached out to Patrick himself.
You seem to have a great deal of interest in my affairs.
You seem to have a great deal of interest in my affairs.
Please don't get the wrong idea.
Please don't get the wrong idea.
I was simply curious.
I was simply curious.
I see. Well, I'll see you soon.
I see. Well, I'll see you soon.
Mi Sook? What brings you here?
Mi Sook? What brings you here?
I came to talk.
I came to talk.
I'm glad you came here. Please have a seat.
I'm glad you came here. Please have a seat.
Actually, after your acquittal and the news of the reinvestigation,
Actually, after your acquittal and the news of the reinvestigation,
I was hoping that while you can still remember,
I was hoping that while you can still remember,
I wanted to have a good, long talk and clear the air.
I wanted to have a good, long talk and clear the air.
I'm sorry I was acquitted.
I'm sorry I was acquitted.
How can you say that?
How can you say that?
Even though it was all a misunderstanding,
Even though it was all a misunderstanding,
and even though I didn't kill Assistant Manager Kim Do Hee,
Y aunque no maté al subgerente Kim Do Hee,
the things I said to her because I was mistaken,
Las cosas que le dije porque me equivoqué,
and my actions...
y mis acciones...
I can't take any of it back or undo it.
No puedo deshacer nada de ello ni retractarme.
So I still feel guilty, and I am truly sorry.
Así que todavía me siento culpable y lo siento mucho.
Thank you for apologising.
Gracias por disculparte.
I know my Do Hee better than anyone.
Conozco a mi Do Hee mejor que nadie.
She would accept a sincere apology and knew how to forgive.
Ella aceptaba una disculpa sincera y sabía perdonar.
Would you like to go with me to see her sometime?
¿Te gustaría ir conmigo a verla alguna vez?
- I can? - Of course.
- ¿Puedo? - Por supuesto.
I'll tell her that her mom has made a new, close friend.
Le diré que su mamá ha hecho una nueva amiga íntima.
Now, you and Mr. Kang Seung Woo...
Ahora, tú y el señor Kang Seung Woo...
are free from the false accusations.
están libres de las falsas acusaciones.
All that's left is to put the real culprit away.
Ahora sólo queda atrapar al verdadero culpable.
So it's such a relief.
Así que es un gran alivio.
I can finally breathe again.
Por fin puedo volver a respirar.
Seung Woo?
¿Seung Woo?
I have to go see my Seung Woo.
Tengo que ir a ver a mi Seung Woo.
It's his first office job, so he must feel out of place.
Es su primer trabajo de oficina, por lo que debe sentirse fuera de lugar.
I'll go with you.
Iré contigo.
If you're going, I'm going with you.
Si tú vas, yo voy contigo.
The number you've called is unavailable.
El número al que has llamado no está disponible.
Connecting to voicemail...
Conectando al correo de voz...
Why isn't Ms. Choi answering her phone?
¿Por qué la Sra. Choi no contesta su teléfono?
Son, are you okay?
Hijo, ¿estás bien?
Are your superiors giving you a hard time?
¿Tus superiores te están haciendo pasar un mal rato?
Honestly, your father is just too much.
Honestamente, tu padre es demasiado.
As if making Jae In start as a regular staffer wasn't enough,
Como si no fuera suficiente que Jae In empezara como miembro regular del personal,
you have to suffer like this too?
¿Tu también tienes que sufrir así?
No, Mom. I'm actually really happy with it.
No, mamá. En realidad estoy muy feliz con ello.
I already made Assistant Manager.
Ya me hicieron asistente de gerente.
Really?
¿En realidad?
Then again, my son can do anything.
De nuevo, mi hijo puede hacer cualquier cosa.
We were having a nice chat,
Estábamos teniendo una agradable charla,
and I guess she suddenly thought of you.
Y supongo que de repente pensó en ti.
Now that she's found you, I'll get going.
Ahora que te ha encontrado, me pondré en marcha.
Okay. Thank you for bringing my mom here.
Está bien. Gracias por traer a mi mamá aquí.
I'll take it from here.
Yo me encargaré de esto desde aquí.
Mom, you know that flower cafe you like?
Mamá, ¿conoces esa cafetería de flores que te gusta?
Do you want to go grab a cup of coffee there?
¿Quieres ir a tomar un café allí?
Oh, I'd love that!
¡Oh, me encantaría eso!
Yun Hee!
¡Yun Hee!
What brings you here without calling first?
¿Qué te trae por aquí sin llamarnos primero?
Ja Young came by my place, and we talked for a bit.
Ja Young vino a mi casa y conversamos un rato.
But then she got a bit disoriented again.
Pero luego se desorientó un poco otra vez.
She said she had to see her son, but I couldn't just let her go alone.
Ella dijo que tenía que ver a su hijo, pero no podía dejarla ir sola.
You did the right thing.
Hiciste lo correcto
Anyway, time to get back to work.
De cualquier modo, es hora de volver al trabajo.
Bring him home for a visit sometime.
Llévalo a casa para visitarlo algún día.
Assistant Manager Kang Seung Woo.
Subgerente Kang Seung Woo.
Really?
¿En realidad?
He grew up oblivious to everything. How is any of this his fault?
Creció ajeno a todo. ¿Cómo es que algo de esto es culpa suya?
Bring him over. I'll make him a home-cooked meal.
Tráelo. Le haré comida casera.
I'm off.
Me voy.
It looks like your mother's starting to warm up to him.
Parece que tu madre está empezando a simpatizar con él.
Right?
¿Bien?
(Executive Director Kang Mi Ran)
(Director ejecutivo Kang Mi Ran)
Did Ja Young stop by while I was in my meeting?
¿Ja Young pasó por aquí mientras estaba en mi reunión?
Yes, I was just on my way back after taking her home.
Sí, estaba de regreso después de llevarla a casa.
Director Do is watching her at home.
El director Do la está vigilando en casa.
Good.
Bien.
From now on,
De aquí en adelante,
she'll probably come looking for me whenever she's not doing well.
Probablemente vendrá a buscarme cuando no esté bien.
I'm sure she will.
Estoy seguro que lo hará.
And I plan on checking in on her more often too.
Y también planeo visitarla más a menudo.
And eventually,
Y eventualmente,
if a time comes...
Si llega un momento...
when she can no longer manage on her own,
Cuando ya no pueda arreglárselas sola,
I'm even considering moving in with her.
Incluso estoy considerando mudarme con ella.
To me, she will always...
Para mí ella siempre será...
be my mom.
sé mi mamá
That's one thing that will never change.
Eso es algo que nunca cambiará.
She's the one who raised me and loved me.
Ella es quien me crio y me amó.
That's because she was my mom.
Eso es porque ella era mi mamá.
So now, it's my turn to give back...
Así que ahora es mi turno de devolver algo...
all the love she has given me.
Todo el amor que me ha dado.
That's what it means to be a decent human being and a son.
Eso es lo que significa ser un ser humano decente y un hijo.
Seung Woo.
Seung Woo.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
I know exactly where you're coming from.
Sé exactamente de dónde vienes.
I know you were worried about me,
Sé que estabas preocupado por mí,
but I'm okay.
pero estoy bien
You should do whatever you want to do.
Debes hacer lo que quieras hacer.
Whatever you want...
Lo que tú quieras...
is what I want too.
Es lo que yo también quiero.
That's all that matters to me.
Eso es todo lo que me importa.
You know, even though my mother is still alive,
Ya sabes, aunque mi madre todavía esté viva,
my birth mother may be Choi Ja Young,
Mi madre biológica puede ser Choi Ja Young,
but today, I really wanted to say this to you.
Pero hoy realmente quería decirte esto.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Mom.
Mamá.
I should get going.
Debería irme.
(YL group)
(Grupo YL)
(Chairman Hwang Gi Chan)
(Presidente Hwang Gi Chan)
I have very high expectations.
Tengo expectativas muy altas.
First, I'd like to take a close look at the pieces.
Primero me gustaría mirar las piezas de cerca.
By all means.
Sin falta.
You'll be even more impressed by the artistry...
Quedarás aún más impresionado por el arte...
when you see it in person.
Cuando lo veas en persona.
It's been a while since you were last in Korea.
Ha pasado algún tiempo desde la última vez que estuviste en Corea.
Have you had a chance to do any sightseeing?
¿Has tenido la oportunidad de hacer algún turismo?
You know, Korea is more dynamic than any other country.
Ya sabes, Corea es más dinámica que cualquier otro país.
I came here to rest, but work has just piled up.
Vine aquí a descansar, pero el trabajo se ha acumulado.
To be honest, more than seeing the tourist sites,
Para ser honesto, más que ver los sitios turísticos,
I've been more curious about what a Korean home is like.
He tenido más curiosidad por saber cómo es un hogar coreano.
Like the way people live,
Al igual que la forma en que vive la gente,
home-cooked meals and their diet, you know.
comidas caseras y su dieta, ya sabes.
I see.
Veo.
I suppose it's because of my Korean roots.
Supongo que es por mis raíces coreanas.
I don't have any relatives here, so I haven't had the chance.
No tengo parientes aquí así que no he tenido oportunidad.
It's much better to have a home base when you're working.
Es mucho mejor tener una base de operaciones cuando estás trabajando.
Staying in a hotel just doesn't feel very grounding.
Alojarse en un hotel simplemente no resulta muy cómodo.
Maybe that's why I've been struggling a bit lately.
Quizás es por eso que he estado luchando un poco últimamente.
Well then, how would you like to stay at my home for a while?
Bueno entonces ¿te gustaría quedarte en mi casa por un tiempo?
That's all right. I couldn't possibly impose.
Está bien. No podría imponerme.
Nonsense, it's no imposition at all.
Tonterías, no es ninguna imposición.
We have a spare room,
Tenemos una habitación libre,
and we can easily set another plate.
y fácilmente podemos poner otro plato.
In fact, why not come over today?
De hecho, ¿por qué no vienes hoy?
Really? Would that be all right?
¿En serio? ¿Estaría bien?
Of course. I invited you, didn't I?
Por supuesto. Te invité, ¿no?
Please make yourself at home.
Por favor, siéntete como en casa.
Excuse me.
Disculpe.
Oh, Tae Ho?
¿Oh, Tae Ho?
What brings you here?
¿Qué te trae por aquí?
Do you have a moment?
¿Tienes un momento?
There's something I could use your help with.
Hay algo en lo que podría necesitar tu ayuda.
Could we maybe talk outside?
¿Podríamos quizás hablar afuera?
It looks like it's about time for lunch.
Parece que ya es hora de almorzar.
Sure.
Seguro.
Mr. Kang, go get some lunch. I'm heading out for some too.
Señor Kang, vaya a almorzar. Yo también voy a ir a buscar algo.
A toy?
¿Un juguete?
It's not for me.
No es para mi
I'm going to be staying at an acquaintance's home for a bit,
Me quedaré en casa de un conocido por un tiempo.
and they have a child.
y tienen un hijo.
I'd like to get them a small gift,
Me gustaría regalarles un pequeño regalo,
but I'm not sure what to get.
pero no estoy seguro de qué comprar.
How old is the kid?
¿Qué edad tiene el niño?
Seven.
Siete.
Let's go. You bought lunch, so let me help.
Vamos. Compraste el almuerzo, así que déjame ayudarte.
You'd do that?
¿Harías eso?
Thanks.
Gracias.
(Chairman Hwang Gi Chan)
(Presidente Hwang Gi Chan)
We're not home. Stop waltzing in and out.
No estamos en casa. Deja de entrar y salir bailando.
Look at this.
Mira esto.
I'm not interested.
No me interesa.
Just look at it.
Sólo míralo.
Look.
Mirar.
See?
¿Ver?
Do you think a woman like that would ever come back to you?
¿Crees que una mujer así volvería alguna vez a ti?
Kang Jae In has absolutely no interest in you.
Kang Jae In no tiene absolutamente ningún interés en ti.
Get over her.
Supérala.
That meeting wasn't about Jae In. It was business with a Designer L.
Esa reunión no era sobre Jae In. Eran negocios con un tal diseñador, L.
Are you out of your mind?
¿Estás loco?
How can you possibly defend her?
¿Cómo podrás defenderla?
Just go home early today.
Hoy simplemente vete temprano a casa.
We have an important guest coming over, so get dinner ready.
Tenemos un invitado importante, así que prepara la cena.
I guess he still sees me as his wife after all.
Supongo que todavía me ve como su esposa después de todo.
Fine. You'll see just how perfect a wife I can be for you.
Bien. Ya verás lo perfecta que puedo ser como esposa para ti.
Who is this person, anyway?
¿Quién es esta persona, de todos modos?
What's all the fuss about?
¿A qué se debe todo este alboroto?
Who is this person we have to impress?
¿Quién es esta persona a la que tenemos que impresionar?
Yes. He's staying with us for a while.
Sí. Se quedará con nosotros por un tiempo.
Mother, be on your best behaviour.
Madre, pórtate lo mejor posible.
A single word from him can move fortunes.
Una sola palabra suya puede cambiar la fortuna.
He must be quite the big shot.
Él debe ser un pez gordo.
Excuse me.
Disculpe.
Welcome, come in.
Bienvenido, entra.
Welcome.
Bienvenido.
You know, you look familiar.
¿Sabes? Me pareces familiar.
Have we met somewhere before?
¿Nos hemos conocido en algún lugar antes?
Ji Ho, you should say hello.
Ji Ho, deberías saludarme.
Hello.
Hola.
Well, hello.
Bueno, hola.
Is your name Ji Ho?
¿Tu nombre es Ji Ho?
Yes.
Sí.
Ta-da!
¡Eso es todo!
A present for you.
Un regalo para ti.
This is my favourite!
¡Éste es mi favorito!
Thank you!
¡Gracias!
Let's get your bags settled before we eat.
Vamos a preparar tus maletas antes de comer.
Honey, I'll show him to his room.
Cariño, le mostraré su habitación.
You stay here with Ji Ho.
Quédate aquí con Ji Ho.
Okay, sure.
Está bien, claro.
Once you're unpacked, come on down and we'll have dinner.
Una vez que hayas desempacado, baja y cenaremos.
Okay. Thank you for having me.
Está bien. Gracias por invitarme.
What do you think you're doing?
¿Qué crees que estás haciendo?
I told you not to pull any stunts!
¡Te dije que no hicieras ninguna tontería!
I haven't done a thing.
No he hecho nada
You're the one who's been pulling stunts.
Eres tú el que ha estado haciendo acrobacias.
Why would you do that?
¿Por qué harías eso?
- That's what I'm here to find out. - What is that supposed to mean?
- Eso es lo que vine a averiguar. - ¿Qué se supone que significa eso?
What exactly have I done?
¿Qué he hecho exactamente?
- Lee Tae Ho. - Catherine.
- Lee Tae Ho. - Catherine.
What have you been doing using my sister's name?
¿Qué has estado haciendo usando el nombre de mi hermana?
- I can explain that. - Hwang Ji Ho.
- Puedo explicarlo. - Hwang Ji Ho.
How long were you planning to hide the fact that he's my son?
¿Cuánto tiempo planeabas ocultar el hecho de que él es mi hijo?
What? What are you talking about?
¿Qué? ¿De qué estás hablando?
Who says he's your son?
¿Quién dice que es tu hijo?
That's not true.
Eso no es verdad
Mom, Dad says to hurry down.
Mamá, papá dice que bajes rápido.
Okay. Go on downstairs, Ji Ho.
Está bien. Baja las escaleras, Ji Ho.
Ji Ho.
Sí, sí.
How about we go downstairs together?
¿Qué tal si bajamos juntos las escaleras?
Please enjoy your meal, Mr. Lee.
Disfrute de su comida, señor Lee.
A spread like this is...
Un spread como este es...
what's called a Korean royal feast, right?
¿Cómo se llama el banquete real coreano, verdad?
I told Mom you're an honoured guest, so it looks like she went all out.
Le dije a mamá que eras un invitado de honor, así que parece que hizo todo lo posible.
I only used the very best ingredients and seasoning.
Sólo utilicé los mejores ingredientes y condimentos.
I'm just asking out of artistic curiosity,
Sólo pregunto por curiosidad artística.
what's the most expensive painting you've ever sold?
¿Cuál es el cuadro más caro que has vendido jamás?
Well, I don't really keep a ranking.
Bueno, realmente no llevo una clasificación.
If you mean the most expensive piece I've brokered recently...
Si te refieres a la pieza más cara que he vendido recientemente...
It was around a hundred million dollars.
Eran alrededor de cien millones de dólares.
A hundred million dollars?
¿Cien millones de dólares?
How much is a hundred million dollars?
¿Cuánto son cien millones de dólares?
Around 100 billion won.
Alrededor de 100 mil millones de wones.
Oh my gosh.
Oh Dios mío.
Here, please, eat up, Mr. Lee.
A ver, señor Lee, coma, por favor.
It's customary to introduce everyone.
Es costumbre presentar a todo el mundo.
Shall I introduce my family?
¿Les presento a mi familia?
That'd be great.
Eso sería genial.
This is the homewrecker.
Este es un destructor de hogares.
Gi Man.
Dale hombre.
What? It's how the online videos say.
¿Qué? Es lo que dicen los videos en línea.
My brother's wife, the homewrecker, stole her friend's husband.
La esposa de mi hermano, la rompehogares, le robó el marido a su amiga.
Is that correct?
¿Es eso correcto?
Hey, Gi Man.
Hola, Gi Man.
You should probably just eat.
Probablemente deberías simplemente comer.
I can't eat fast. I get indigestion. You should eat slowly and chew well.
No puedo comer rápido. Me da indigestión. Deberías comer despacio y masticar bien.
Okay, fine. Slowly then.
Está bien. Despacio entonces.
Please can we just eat first?
Por favor ¿podemos comer primero?
Okay.
Bueno.
As you've probably figured out,
Como probablemente te habrás dado cuenta,
my brother suffered a head injury in an accident.
Mi hermano sufrió una lesión en la cabeza en un accidente.
So he's a little...
Así que es un pequeño...
Please bear with him.
Por favor, ten paciencia con él.
I'm so down. Maybe fillers would cheer me up.
Estoy muy deprimida. Quizás algo de relleno me animaría.
And I do need to get another facelift.
Y realmente necesito hacerme otro lavado de cara.
What's your game?
¿Cual es tu juego?
I told you he was not your son. He's not.
Te dije que no era tu hijo. No lo es.
Should we get a paternity test?
¿Deberíamos hacernos una prueba de paternidad?
Fine.
Bien.
He may be your son, biologically.
Él podría ser tu hijo biológicamente.
But he's grown up his whole life believing Gi Chan is his father.
Pero creció toda su vida creyendo que Gi Chan es su padre.
And you told him I was dead?
¿Y le dijiste que estaba muerto?
I did. After we split, you were dead to me.
Lo hice. Después de que nos separamos, estabas muerto para mí.
Let's be honest. We were both dirt-poor.
Seamos honestos. Los dos éramos muy pobres.
We were in no position to have and raise a child,
No estábamos en condiciones de tener y criar un hijo,
and I didn't want to have the baby.
y yo no quería tener el bebé.
I didn't want to pass my poverty on to my child.
No quería transmitirle mi pobreza a mi hijo.
And then I met a man who could provide for my child.
Y luego conocí a un hombre que podía cuidar de mi hijo.
My husband.
Mi marido.
Our Ji Ho has grown up wanting for nothing.
Nuestro Ji Ho creció sin carecer de nada.
I've given him everything he could ever want.
Le he dado todo lo que alguna vez pudo desear.
I'm not going to let our family fall apart.
No voy a dejar que nuestra familia se desmorone.
I'm not just going to stand by and watch.
No me quedaré simplemente mirando.
If you do anything to hurt my Ji Ho,
Si haces algo que lastime a mi Ji Ho,
I will make you regret it.
Haré que te arrepientas.
I'll kill you.
Te mataré.
So just tell me.
Entonces solo dime.
What is it you want?
¿Qué es lo que quieres?
Tell me!
¡Dime!
I have no intention...
No tengo ninguna intención...
of turning a happy kid's life upside down.
de poner patas arriba la vida de un niño feliz.
Do you really mean that?
¿En serio lo dices en serio?
I do, as long as you and your family...
Lo haré, siempre y cuando tú y tu familia...
are a good influence on Ji Ho.
son una buena influencia para Ji Ho.
What's that supposed to mean?
¿Qué se supone que significa eso?
Don't get so defensive.
No te pongas tan a la defensiva.
If you're a mother who can face her child...
Si eres una madre que puede enfrentar a su hijo...
with a clear conscience,
con la conciencia tranquila,
then I have no desire to interfere.
Entonces no tengo ningún deseo de interferir.
What is that supposed to mean?
¿Qué se supone que significa eso?
What do I have to be ashamed of?
¿De qué tengo que avergonzarme?
Well...
Bien...
I don't have all the details just yet.
Aún no tengo todos los detalles.
Then why would you say something like that?
Entonces ¿por qué dirías algo así?
Is that what Kang Jae In said?
¿Eso es lo que dijo Kang Jae In?
That I should be ashamed of myself?
¿Que debería avergonzarme de mí mismo?
You know the Korean saying,
Ya conoces el dicho coreano:
"A guilty conscience needs no accuser."
"Una conciencia culpable no necesita acusador".
Because that's certainly what it sounds like to me.
Porque eso es ciertamente lo que me suena a mí.
Let's not go over this again.
No repasemos esto otra vez.
If you're truly a fit mother,
Si realmente eres una madre en forma,
I'll go right back to the U.S.
Regresaré a los Estados Unidos enseguida.
Deal?
¿Trato?
Hard at work, I see.
Veo que estás trabajando duro.
I'm a hard worker by nature.
Soy una persona trabajadora por naturaleza.
Are you free this evening?
¿Estas libre esta noche?
I was hoping we could have dinner.
Esperaba que pudiéramos cenar.
Is it for the drink you gave me for the detective the other day?
¿Es por la bebida que me diste para el detective el otro día?
I did promise it'd be my treat. Sure.
Te prometí que sería mi invitación. Claro.
Okay, let's meet up after work.
Está bien, nos vemos después del trabajo.
Sounds good.
Suena bien.
I'm just going to grab some coffee.
Sólo voy a tomar un café.
Why do you have to report that to me?
¿Por qué tienes que informarme eso?
I have no intention of getting in the way of an office romance.
No tengo intención de interferir en un romance de oficina.
I guess that's what you mean, right?
Supongo que eso es lo que quieres decir, ¿verdad?
We don't have anything work-related to talk about today, do we?
No tenemos nada relacionado con el trabajo que hablar hoy, ¿verdad?
Oh, this isn't about work.
Oh, esto no se trata de trabajo.
Did I mention Yun Hee wanted to have Seung Woo over?
¿Mencioné que Yun Hee quería invitar a Seung Woo?
Yes, and you also mentioned you told her he was your son.
Sí, y también mencionaste que le dijiste que era tu hijo.
I'm planning on taking him to dinner with them tonight.
Estoy planeando llevarlo a cenar con ellos esta noche.
Are you sure that's okay with taking only Mr. Kang Seung Woo?
¿Estás seguro de que está bien llevar solo al Sr. Kang Seung Woo?
Seung Woo has done nothing wrong.
Seung Woo no ha hecho nada malo.
If Seung Woo can only meet them first,
Si Seung Woo pudiera conocerlos primero,
and it's a chance to naturally get closer to your family,
y es una oportunidad de acercarse naturalmente a su familia,
that would be wonderful.
Eso sería maravilloso.
Next time we get a chance,
La próxima vez que tengamos la oportunidad,
the three of us can go together.
Los tres podemos ir juntos.
Don't worry about me,
No te preocupes por mí,
I hope you two have a nice, cosy dinner.
Espero que tengáis una cena agradable y acogedora.
How do you know when my break is?
¿Cómo sabes cuando es mi descanso?
How do you always show up the second I step out for coffee?
¿Cómo haces para aparecer siempre en el mismo momento en que salgo a tomar un café?
I can't really explain it. I just think of you, and you appear.
Realmente no puedo explicarlo. Solo pienso en ti y apareces.
It's like you're sending me signals or something.
Es como si me estuvieras enviando señales o algo así.
I'm definitely not sending you any signals.
Definitivamente no te estoy enviando ninguna señal.
I'm on your side, no matter what.
Estoy de tu lado, pase lo que pase.
I know Gi Chan was completely in the wrong.
Sé que Gi Chan estaba completamente equivocado.
I don't know much, but he did cheat and treat Jae In terribly.
No sé mucho, pero él engañó y trató terriblemente a Jae In.
But that has nothing to do with me. I've never taken his side.
Pero eso no tiene nada que ver conmigo. Nunca me he puesto de su lado.
I swear.
Lo juro.
Besides, once I get married, I'm out of that family anyway.
Además, una vez que me case, de todos modos estaré fuera de esa familia.
So I'm telling you I will always be on your side.
Así que te digo que siempre estaré de tu lado.
I'll put it in writing right now if you want.
Lo pondré por escrito ahora mismo si quieres.
What will you do if I actually have it notarized?
¿Qué harás si finalmente lo hago notarizar?
I wouldn't care. It's what my heart wants.
No me importaría. Es lo que mi corazón quiere.
How can you be so sure about this?
¿Cómo puedes estar tan seguro de esto?
Because you're the one I like.
Porque eres quien me gusta.
I believe in making clear whose side you're on.
Creo en dejar claro de qué lado estás.
Especially when it's about someone I care about,
Especialmente cuando se trata de alguien que me importa,
they need to know, without a doubt, that I'm on their side.
Necesitan saber, sin lugar a dudas, que estoy de su lado.
All right, here we are.
Muy bien, aquí estamos.
Come on in.
Adelante, entra.
Hello.
Hola.
This is for you.
Esto es para ti.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Thank you so much for having me.
Muchas gracias por invitarme.
Patrick invited me over for a home-cooked meal.
Patrick me invitó a su casa a comer una comida casera.
We're glad you could make it.
Nos alegra que hayas podido venir.
We've all been looking forward to meeting you.
Todos estábamos deseando conocerte.
Bo Ram, say hello.
Bo Ram, di hola.
Hi, handsome! I'm Kim Bo Ram.
¡Hola, guapo! Soy Kim Bo Ram.
Bo Ram, I wouldn't call him handsome.
Bo Ram, yo no lo llamaría guapo.
He's on par with me.
Él está a mi par.
Kids don't lie.
Los niños no mienten.
He's way more handsome than you.
Él es mucho más guapo que tú.
Like by this much!
¡Me gusta por esto!
I like him.
Me gusta él.
- Please have a seat. Okay? - Oh, sure.
—Por favor, siéntese. ¿De acuerdo? —Claro.
- Let's sit. - Right this way.
-Sentémonos.-Por aquí.
It's not much, but please enjoy.
No es mucho, pero disfrútalo.
Did you really make all this for me?
¿De verdad hiciste todo esto para mí?
I wasn't sure what you'd like.
No estaba seguro de lo que te gustaría.
I hope the seasoning is okay.
Espero que el condimento esté bien.
This is absolutely delicious.
Esto es absolutamente delicioso.
This is nothing. My sister's a master at cooking.
Esto no es nada. Mi hermana es una maestra en la cocina.
Here, try one. It'll knock your socks off.
Toma, prueba uno. Te dejará boquiabierto.
Here you go.
Aquí tienes.
Good!
¡Bien!
See?
¿Ver?
You have some too, Do Yun.
Tú también tienes algo, Do Yun.
You enjoy your food too, Bo Ram.
Disfruta tu comida también, Bo Ram.
Okay.
Bueno.
All right. Mom, you eat up too!
Está bien. ¡Mamá, come tú también!
Oh, goodness, all right.
Oh, Dios, está bien.
Honestly, you'd think we were doing the wave.
Honestamente, uno pensaría que estábamos haciendo la ola.
Hey, you eat too.
Oye, tú también comes.
Oh, right. Here, Bo Ram, have some of this too.
Ah, cierto. Toma, Bo Ram, toma un poco de esto también.
Come on.
Vamos.
- Let's eat. - Okay.
- Vamos a comer. - Está bien.
- How is it? Is it good? - It's delicious.
¿Qué tal? ¿Está bueno? Está delicioso.
Good. Eat up, everyone.
Bien. A comer, todos.
Did they leave all right?
¿Se fueron bien?
Yes, at first, he was dragging his feet,
Sí, al principio se resistía,
but he must've had a good time.
pero debe haberlo pasado bien.
He asked to be invited again.
Pidió ser invitado nuevamente.
Thanks, Yun Hee.
Gracias, Yun Hee.
He's really grown up well.
Realmente ha crecido muy bien.
Even if Ja Young said she resented him,
Incluso si Ja Young dijo que estaba resentida con él,
you can see she raised him lovingly.
Se puede ver que ella lo crio con amor.
You can tell if a child was raised with love...
Se puede saber si un niño fue criado con amor...
or without it.
o sin ella.
Oh Seong.
Oh Seong.
He'll find out anyway, so just tell him.
Se enterará de todos modos, así que díselo.
Putting it off won't solve anything.
Posponerlo no solucionará nada.
He'll be so shocked. You need to be there for him.
Se sorprenderá mucho. Tienes que estar ahí para él.
Right?
¿Bien?
I tell myself I have to tell him, but the words just won't come out.
Me digo a mí misma que tengo que decírselo, pero las palabras no me salen.
You're making it complicated by overthinking things.
Lo estás complicando al pensar demasiado las cosas.
Stop thinking and just tell him.
Deja de pensar y díselo.
That saying, "blood is thicker than water."
Ese dicho, "la sangre es más espesa que el agua".
I saw that today.
Vi eso hoy.
You two look alike.
Ustedes dos se parecen.
We do?
¿Lo hacemos?
So we do look alike.
Entonces sí que nos parecemos.
Ms. Jae In? It's Bo Ram.
¿Señorita Jae In? Soy Bo Ram.
What are you doing?
¿Qué estás haciendo?
Bo Ram, you shouldn't call when she's busy.
Bo Ram, no deberías llamarla cuando esté ocupada.
I called because I missed you.
Te llamé porque te extrañé.
My uncle is here with me too.
Mi tío también está aquí conmigo.
He's working.
Él está trabajando.
Okay. Bye, Ms. Jae In.
Está bien. Adiós, Sra. Jae In.
Uncle Do Yun, "working overtime" means working really late, right?
Tío Do Yun, "trabajar horas extras" significa trabajar hasta muy tarde, ¿verdad?
Yes. How do you know that word?
Sí. ¿Cómo sabes esa palabra?
Mom used to say that at her company.
Mamá solía decir eso en su empresa.
Ms. Jae In is working at her office right now, right?
La Sra. Jae In está trabajando en su oficina ahora mismo, ¿verdad?
Probably.
Probablemente.
But it's scary and dangerous for her to go home alone at night.
Pero para ella es aterrador y peligroso volver a casa sola por la noche.
Let's go meet her.
Vamos a conocerla.
What?
¿Qué?
Come on, please?
¿Vamos, por favor?
Should we?
¿Deberíamos?
- Ms. Jae In! - Bo Ram!
- ¡Señorita Jae In! - ¡Bo Ram!
- Hi! Have you been okay? - Yes.
—¡Hola! ¿Estás bien? —Sí.
Have you been waiting long?
¿Llevas mucho tiempo esperando?
No, I just came down.
No, solo bajé.
- How about work? All done? - Yes.
¿Qué tal el trabajo? ¿Ya terminaste? - Sí.
- Bo Ram, I missed you so much. - Me too.
- Bo Ram, te extrañé mucho. - Yo también.
- Okay. - What should we get to eat?
- Está bien. - ¿Qué comemos?
- Ice cream! - Ice cream?
- ¡Helado! - ¿Helado?
Hey, you already had one on the way here.
Oye, ya tenías uno en camino hacia aquí.
Honey!
¡Miel!
Eun Ho!
¡Eun Ho!
This is so good.
Esto es muy bueno.
Uncle, who's that man?
Tío, ¿quién es ese hombre?
Why is he taking Ms. Jae In?
¿Por qué se lleva a la Sra. Jae In?
Well, I guess she had other plans.
Bueno, supongo que tenía otros planes.
Are you crazy?
¿Estás loco?
Stop the car.
Detener el coche.
I said stop! Stop the car!
¡Dije para! ¡Para el coche!
Hwang Gi Chan!
¡Hwang Gi Chan!
What do you think you're doing?
¿Qué crees que estás haciendo?
A kidnapping? What's wrong with you?
¿Un secuestro? ¿Qué te pasa?
I don't even know why I'm doing this.
Ni siquiera sé por qué estoy haciendo esto.
- How can you not know? - I don't know! I just don't!
—¿Cómo es posible que no lo sepas? —¡No lo sé! ¡Simplemente no lo sé!
I think I can't live without you.
Creo que no puedo vivir sin ti.
I can't stand seeing you with some other guy!
¡No soporto verte con otro chico!
I guess I'm still in love with you.
Supongo que todavía estoy enamorado de ti.
(Queen's House)
(Casa de la Reina)
What do you think you're doing?
¿Qué crees que estás haciendo?
Don't you dare lay a hand on Jae In again!
¡No te atrevas a ponerle la mano encima a Jae In otra vez!
- Who do you think you are? - Because I love Jae In.
-¿Quién te crees que eres? -Porque amo a Jae In.
Just a year before Ji Ho came along,
Apenas un año antes de que apareciera Ji Ho,
didn't you say you'd rather not have kids?
¿No dijiste que preferirías no tener hijos?
That's what Chairman Hwang Gi Chan told me.
Eso es lo que me dijo el presidente Hwang Gi Chan.
- Well, you see... - A year before Ji Ho came along?
- Bueno, verás... - ¿Un año antes de que apareciera Ji Ho?
That was before you and I had even met.
Eso fue antes de que tú y yo nos conociéramos.
You keep showing up at home and work just to torment me!
¡Sigues apareciendo en casa y en el trabajo sólo para atormentarme!
Go back to the U.S. right now!
¡Regresa a los EE.UU. ahora mismo!